hey everyone thanks for listening to the
grow your life podcast my name is
jeremiah krakowski and on this podcast i
show course creators coaches trainers
authors speakers consultants and leaders
anybody who's in business online the
strategies the tips the mindset tricks
what you can do on the internet how to
use direct response marketing in a way
that gets results now today i'm going to
talk more on mindset we're going to talk
about how to not be a victim in your
business and how to create a winning
mindset
for your business the truth is is this
is that a lot of times i see people in
business they're putting themselves last
they find it hard to say no they're
they're always blaming other people and
they're suffering what's called this
victim mentality this victim mentality
is that they're powerless to everything
else that's going on around them it's
outside of their control and that if
only all these other things would change
then they could be successful and it
really it becomes a self-fulfilling
prophecy if you believe that you're
powerless you won't take action to
change your situation if you don't take
action nothing will change and it
becomes this loop and so the victim
mentality is opposite of what will allow
you to be successful in business okay so
that's what i want to talk about today i
want to talk about
dealing with this victim mentality i
want to talk about dealing with this
mindset and how you can start to take
more ownership in your life i struggled
with this for a long time
dealing with the victim mentality the
victim mindset blaming everybody else
not taking responsibility for why my
business was going a certain way i had a
desire for it and things weren't working
out and i talk with my clients a lot
about this they're like yeah my spouse
bothers me all the time
uh you know my my dog died and so i
can't do this or my my family uh had a
family member that got sick and then it
basically derails their business for for
years like two years they're still using
the the death of the family member for
why they can't succeed and i wanna have
compassion for that you need to grieve
the big reason behind this is that we're
not allowing ourselves to feel those
feelings in grief and we're actually
trying to stuff them away okay
that's one of the biggest issues with
this is that when we don't allow
ourselves to feel the pain we keep
reiterating the victim mindset because
we're trying to validate to ourselves
that we have permission to feel this way
and then we end up focusing on it that's
what was going on for me as i kept
re-traumatizing myself re-putting myself
through the victim scenario every time
that i would bring it up and use it as a
crutch as an excuse and and for me you
know a big one was when i started this
business right now the one that i'm
building right now we're about 160
podcast episodes in this was four years
ago um i had been working for my mom and
i was no longer working for her and so i
had a my income was dropped down and i
was making excuses and operating as a
victim blaming my my wife and my family
and blaming my mom and blaming everybody
else around me for why i couldn't be
successful in business
it was ridiculous and so it was a it was
blocking me by playing the victim
from even doing the things that i know
that i was called to do how many of you
are blocking yourself from doing the
thing that you were born to do because
of these situations that are going on in
your life or maybe you're like you know
my spouse won't allow me
to build my business or my kids won't
allow me my kids my kids i got no time
because of the kids and i can't do
anything because i got church and i got
people and i got responsibilities and i
got my friends that's the victim mindset
that's the victim mentality you are a
victim to something that other people
did to you and are doing to you and will
continue to do to you and that you
believe that they will do to you and so
you do all of your actions to avoid
trying to get those things done to you
and it's no responsibility of your own
it's everybody else's fault
and so that mindset is prevalent in
people that struggle to succeed they'll
blame their wife they'll blame their
boss they'll blame their job they'll
blame their ex-boss they'll blame
whatever it is that they need they'll
blame the government they'll blame joe
biden they'll blame donald trump they'll
blame obama and even george bush or
ronald reagan who cares you know what i
mean like it goes back as far as people
need to create a narrative for why they
can't be successful
it's crazy
it's insanity
and and if you're listening to this
right now and you're you you you still
can continue to listen to this podcast
i believe that you're somebody that
doesn't want to live this way
that doesn't want to operate this way
that you got goals you got dreams you
got visions you got ideas you got things
that you want to do
but this mentality has been holding you
back
and you're ready to say no more i'm done
with the victim mindset i'm done with
the victim mentality
either that or you're gonna write me and
be really angry
at everything that i just said
because i'm
not compassionate of your situation okay
one of those two things is going to
happen if you're listening to this
listen i
do
understand the pain
of this
and i was somebody that was blaming
everybody for my life my whole life i
blamed the fact that i was homeschooled
for why
i
struggled to communicate with people and
the fact that how i was raised in the
church and all this other stuff that i
was blaming for why my life was not
going how i wanted it to until i took
personal
responsibility
my friends we have to live our life
where we stop blaming and making other
people responsible for our life that's
called codependency
when you study when you read there's a
book called codependent no more it'll
help you with this where we're
codependent on other people and other
people are the reason why we feel live
talk and operate the way that we are
that
is
by design
a a constant victim cycle
where you are constantly the victim of
of another person
other people are a victim of you and
we're responsible for other people's
emotions thoughts and feelings and
managing those things as our is our
primary
responsibility a way that this manifests
in relationships is you know if if
you're afraid of angering and upsetting
people and then your happiness is tied
to somebody else's emotional response
okay and it becomes this addictive cycle
that we get in we get into this with
with other things in our life could be
an inanimate object
you could have there's
there's uh it's called um
traffic trauma
somebody crashes their car
and now they lose their job they lose
their dignity they lose their their
their life because they made a mistake
and so they're blaming the situation
for why they can't
get to where they want to be and my
friends we have to divorce this thinking
we have to break up with this thinking
that tells us
that things outside of us are the reason
why
our life is going how it is
and stop making excuses for why it is
now that's why i said again grief is
important there's a book called rising
strong
by brene brown
that's really good on this topic about
when you get knocked down and life beats
you up
how to get back up again and what it
breaks down if i can re like summarize
it for you is you have to feel the grief
you have to feel the pain
you have to feel that pain and
acknowledge it
so that it no longer has control over
you
until you do it will continue to have
control over you
okay and so that's what working with a
therapist and even psychology can help
us with is being able to release those
feelings so that we don't release them
on everybody else around
us see that's what ends up happening
when we're not releasing it in a safe
way and letting it go and forgiving
ourselves and the situation accepting
things for how they are accepting that
our plans didn't work out accepting that
our goals didn't go exactly how we
needed them to be to feel safe and
secure and we're okay with that and
we're okay with that things are not
going exactly how we wanted them to in
our perfect little
fairy tale plan that we made up in our
head
and that we can
instead
grieve the fact that the version of our
life that we thought was gonna happen
didn't happen
we're okay with that right
it was a big grief for me when i started
my own business i had a version of my
life and my future
of working with my mom and her company
that i had to grieve in starting my own
business in order to allow me to even
start to do the work that i'm doing
today
to be able to communicate this way
to be able to talk to be able to make
videos to be able to make content to be
able to impact people with courses and
trainings
and to make
an
influence on people's lives so that they
can be more successful as a business
owner and so my friends we gotta break
up with the victim mindset
we to break up with the victim mentality
that says that that that it's other
people's fault
and it's the situation's fault
for why
i can't
build my business for why i have been
unable for two years to do anything now
now that accept that accept that for two
years you've been doing that
and then change it tomorrow
change it like that it takes that long
to change it
no more dwelling on what happened no
more dwelling on the past no more
dwelling on the pain no more dwelling on
all that
feel it you felt it
to heal it the goal is to heal it you
want to feel it to heal it
not to sit in it and feel it and bathe
in it
and re re
create
the the past see a lot of us are trying
to recreate the past that we wished
happened by recreating the trauma
in our life
by reiterating the story in our head
and it doesn't help anybody
it's a choice to do that it's a choice
to do that my friends
and it's also a choice to then step up
rise strong
after you grieve after you heal
to build your business to show up
to learn new skill sets that you didn't
have before to learn the skill set of
communication and talking with people in
direct response marketing and growing
your business and getting your message
out there see your mass
that story that scenario of what
happened to you that's your story that
you're then going to use to influence
and impact people so you when you heal
from that story you're able to share
just like i did
not from the pain but from the scars
that are healed and you say you know
what you don't have to live that way and
you can inspire a whole generation of
people
to no longer live that way
to no longer operate that way
your story could be the message that
will change a generation
it could be
when you choose to not live
in the victim mindset
and you choose to take personal
responsibility
you know one of my two of my favorite
books on this topic
um
the meditations of marcus aurelius
really good
it was written um
about as long ago as the bible was
written he was a roman emperor and he
wrote in his journal
stuff that's very relevant today
about pain and about dealing with
the mental anxiety of leading the
largest empire in the world
and that
learning from that is called stoicism
learning from that
allows us it gives us a framework to
operate from to not let things defeat us
but instead we rise again we rise
stronger another great book is extreme
ownership by jaco willink
how the u.s navy seals lead and win and
it'll help you lead others and lead your
own life and how to take personal
responsibility personal ownership for
how things are going in your life
instead of blaming and playing the
victim game instead you can take back
control of your life and start to create
the life that you want
another great book how to do the work by
nicole lepra
is about how to identify
some of those pains in our life to feel
some of the unfelt grief
in order to heal
in order to no longer live in a victim
state of mind okay my friends
so hopefully this has been
helpful for you hopefully it's given you
a lot to think about go check out some
of those books
if you got questions about this i'd love
to hear from you on my social media
i'd love to talk with you listen if you
want to build a business if you want to
be successful
somebody who is a course creator or
coach somebody that makes an impact on
the world with your story you're going
to have to commit yourself to personal
development and growing in the areas
that previously
you needed help in that previously held
you back you can't make excuses anymore
it's time to start to take action and
move forward
we'll talk soon everybody have a good
one